<mvc:View xmlns:mvc="sap.ui.core.mvc" xmlns="sap.m"

                     xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<Page>

  <content>

    <html:div style="font-size:120%;">Double Exponential Smoothing model is suitable to model the time series with trend but without seasonality. In
the model there are two kinds of smoothed quantities: smoothed signal and smoothed trend.
<html:br></html:br>
PAL provides two methods of double exponential smoothing: Holt's linear exponential smoothing and additive
damped trend Holt's linear exponential smoothing. The Holt’s linear exponential smoothing displays a
constant trend indefinitely into the future. Empirical evidence shows that the Holt's linear method tends to
over-forecast. A parameter that is used to damp the trend could improve the situation.<html:br></html:br>For single exponential smoothing, let St be the smoothed value for the t-th time period. Mathematically:
<html:br></html:br>

<html:b>Holt's Linear Exponential Smoothing</html:b><html:br></html:br>
Let St and bt be the smoothed value and smoothed trend for the (t+1)-th time period, respectively. The following rules are satisfied:
<html:br></html:br>
S0 = x0 <html:br></html:br>
b0 = x1 – x0 <html:br></html:br>
St = αxt + (1 – α) (St-1 + bt-1) <html:br></html:br>
bt = β (St – St–1) + (1 – β) bt-1 <html:br></html:br> Where α, β∈(0,1) are two user specified parameters. The model can be understood as two coupled Single
Exponential Smoothing models, and forecast can be made by the following equation: <html:br></html:br>
FT+m = ST + mbT <html:br></html:br>

<html:b>Prerequisites</html:b>
<html:p> ●  No missing or null data in the inputs. The algorithm will issue errors when encountering null values.<html:br></html:br>
 ●  The data is numeric, not categorical.<html:br></html:br>

</html:p>

<html:b>Procedure Generation</html:b>
<html:p> CALL SYS.AFLLANG_WRAPPER_PROCEDURE_CREATE (‘AFLPAL’, ‘DOUBLESMOOTH’, ‘schema_name’, 'procedure_name', signature_table);</html:p>

</html:div>

  </content>

</Page>

</mvc:View>
